
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<id>https://espy.world/</id>
<title>espy.world</title>
<subtitle>Mad scientist experimentations.</subtitle>
<link href="https://espy.world" rel="alternate"/>
<link href="https://espy.world/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
<updated>2024-11-29T16:51:00-07:00</updated>

<entry>
    <id>https://espy.world/log/2024/nov/%5BNew%20Art%5D%20Vision.html</id>
    <title>[New Art] Vision</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;img src="/art/2024/vision-1.png"/&gt; &lt;img src="/art/2024/vision-2.png"/&gt; &lt;p&gt; This was previously posted on Cohost, but now I've finally shared it everywhere. &lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://espy.world/log/2024/nov/%5BNew%20Art%5D%20Vision.html" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2024-11-29T16:51:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2024-11-29T16:51:00-07:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>espimyte</name>
    </author>
    <category term="art"/>
</entry>

<entry>
    <id>https://espy.world/log/2024/nov/%5BNew%20Art%5D%20Rise%20%26%20Shine.html</id>
    <title>[New Art] Rise &amp; Shine</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;img src="/art/2024/rise-and-shine.png"/&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://espy.world/log/2024/nov/%5BNew%20Art%5D%20Rise%20%26%20Shine.html" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2024-11-24T14:51:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2024-11-24T14:51:00-07:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>espimyte</name>
    </author>
    <category term="art"/>
</entry>

<entry>
    <id>https://espy.world/log/2024/nov/%5BNew%20Art%5D%20Teeth%20and%20Metamorphosis.html</id>
    <title>[New Art] Teeth and Metamorphosis</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;img src="/art/2024/teeth-and-metamorphosis.png"/&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://espy.world/log/2024/nov/%5BNew%20Art%5D%20Teeth%20and%20Metamorphosis.html" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2024-11-18T14:54:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2024-11-18T14:54:00-07:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>espimyte</name>
    </author>
    <category term="art"/>
</entry>

<entry>
    <id>https://espy.world/log/2024/nov/Characters%20page%20is%20live%21.html</id>
    <title>Characters page is live!</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt; Greetings! I have been hard at work creating the &lt;a href="/characters.html"&gt;characters&lt;/a&gt; page! It is now up and running! &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; It is not what I want it to be just yet, but for now this works just to have the page exist at all. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; That's what I really like about working on this website I think. The fact that it exists already and can be shared with other people. And it can still continue to grow, instead of being a one-and-done thing. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Goodness. I want to redesign a LOT of my characters. They've been gathering dust. Hopefully not for much longer. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; There's also a lot of random art I haven't directly shared online. A lot of that is now hosted here on my site and can be viewed &lt;a href="/gallery.html?room=scrap"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; in the gallery now, if you wish to peruse. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; I'm going to briefly summarize the framework I currently have as of writing for the chracters page, plus some notes on the design of it (also as of writing), and a couple of WIPs! &lt;/p&gt; &lt;h1&gt;A BRIEF SUMMARY OF THE FRAMEWORK&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt; Of course, I do NOT want to manually create every single character page. Plus, if I make a change to the way a character page looks, I'll have to update that for every single character. I don't wanna do that. So, I wrote a python script that generates a static HTML page for each character based on a template. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Of course, the script is not a mind reader. It needs data so it knows what to populate the pages with. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2&gt;ORGANIZING AND STORING DATA&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;I have shared my mind with the script!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; I have two &lt;code&gt;.json&lt;/code&gt; files, one for worlds and characters, and the other for art. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The worlds and characters JSON file is structured into two parts: worlds, and characters (of course). &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Both the worlds and characters part of the JSON file are &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Associative_array"&gt;dictionaries&lt;/a&gt;, with the keys being an id I've assigned to each world/character (typically a shortened version of the name), and the values being data such as the full name, description, and etcetera. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The art JSON file has two parts also, art and credits.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The art part of the art JSON file is an &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Array_(data_structure)"&gt;array&lt;/a&gt;, with each entry in the array holding data such as the link to the art (all hosted on my server as of writing), the date of the art, which characters appear in the art, and, if the art was made by someone that isn't me, credit. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The credit part of the art JSON file is another dictionary which maps the name of an artist to their label (like their name) and a link to them. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; I made the credit part cuz I was getting really tired of having to input the same name and link for credit on toyhouse so I decided to make it so I only have to do that once. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The gallery itself also has a bit of a rework on the backend since I'm now using the &lt;code&gt;art.json&lt;/code&gt; file to populate it instead of manually populating each section. If I want to include a piece of art in the gallery, there's a category attribute I can give it. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;h1&gt;TRADING CARD INSPIRED DESIGN&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt; I really like the look and feel of TCG cards! I'm also fascinated by the culture around trading card games as well. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; As some may know, I've been collecting Espeon cards, and Yugioh was also a huge influence on me. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;So each character is card!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;img src="/img/embed/characters-1.png"/&gt; &lt;p&gt;[CAPTION] Eight characters, shown as small and simple cards. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;img src="/img/embed/characters-2.png"/&gt; &lt;p&gt;[CAPTION] A character image in a frame that resembles a trading card. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; It's a lot more simple than a real trading card. It was gonna be more complex (like what they would do if they were part of an actual card game), but I found that it really wasn't good for displaying information and started to draw attention away from the art. But I still like it, even if it is simple like this! &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The main elements that I tried to include to help make this feel a bit like a trading card are the following: &lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;7:10 ratio&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Curved corners&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Name on a row at the top of the card&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; Symbols on the top right, on the same row as the name (usually representing stuff like affinities or cost) &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Illustration credit at the bottom&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;h1&gt;WIPS&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;img src="/img/embed/characters-wip-1.png"/&gt; &lt;img src="/img/embed/characters-wip-2.png"/&gt; &lt;p&gt;And that's all I have to share for now!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Hope you enjoy,&lt;br/&gt;Espy&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://espy.world/log/2024/nov/Characters%20page%20is%20live%21.html" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2024-11-15T07:44:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2024-11-15T07:44:00-07:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>espimyte</name>
    </author>
    <category term="site"/>
	<category term="code"/>
	<category term="art"/>
</entry>

<entry>
    <id>https://espy.world/log/2024/nov/Guestbook%20open%21.html</id>
    <title>Guestbook open!</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt; Hello! I've had quite a month. I hope you all had a good Halloween, if that is a relevant holiday to you. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; This log post is simply here to inform you that the &lt;a href="/guestbook.html"&gt;guestbook&lt;/a&gt; is now open! &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; I want to make it look better in the future, but right now I just wanted to prioritize it existing at all. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The background of the guestbook at current is a hue-shift of a render of my 3D test environment. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;img src="/img/embed/experiment.png"/&gt; &lt;p&gt;[CAPTION] The aforementioned 3D test environment, which is the background of the guestbook at writing. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Feel free to leave a message, if you desire!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Here comes fall,&lt;br/&gt;Espy&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://espy.world/log/2024/nov/Guestbook%20open%21.html" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2024-11-05T04:44:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2024-11-05T04:44:00-07:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>espimyte</name>
    </author>
    <category term="site"/>
</entry>

<entry>
    <id>https://espy.world/log/2024/oct/Index%20and%20Home%20Revamp%21.html</id>
    <title>Index and Home Revamp!</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt; &lt;b&gt;AT LAST!&lt;/b&gt; I have finished revamping both the index and home to the bare minimum satisfactory level that I desired. The first of my many plans for the site have spun into motion. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; As per usual, I have put much of my free time and energy into this revamp, and if you must know, I enjoyed every bit of it. Miraculously, doing web design for my own site has been one of the most fulfilling things I've experienced. If only this could apply to other creative mediums in my life! I do hope that this trend continues. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I'm going to give a quick rundown of the resulting revamps below.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr/&gt; &lt;h1&gt;INDEX&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;div class="image-row"&gt; &lt;img src="/img/embed/new-index-oct-2024.png" style="width: 500px"/&gt; &lt;img src="/img/embed/old-index-oct-2024.png" style="width: 500px"/&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;[CAPTION] [FIRST] New index, [SECOND] Old index&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Earlier while I was developing this website, I was determined to make sure it was entirely mobile friendly. And the old index was indeed mobile friendly! But as I perused other websites, something felt missing. I was missing the &lt;i&gt;maximilism&lt;/i&gt; that I wished for, and neglecting the desktop experience! &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; It also made all the layouts of my website very predictable. A single column, with related items all in a row. I wanted something more complex. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; And so, I've decided to shift over to a new direction! I am still determined to make sure the site is mobile friendly, but I also want to make sure the desktop users are not neglected! &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; My goal for this website now is to try and make every page feel like a full visual experience. This index is the first step in this quest of mine. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; I was inspired by drawings I've seen of characters with their innards exposed. I was particurally captivated by this one illustration of someone with mechanical innards. I've decided to make my own creature with mechanical innards. I made a demon! This is based on concepts I was developing for a new sona (which has now become a character instead). &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; I originally wanted to put something like my current sona on the index, but to be honest, I really didn't want my sona to be the face of the site. I wanted to represent concepts that I felt that I identified with. And for me, that's demons and machines. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; I've also designed a bit of a "logo" for my name! It's an ambigram, meaning that it can be read both rightside up and upside down. It's not very comprehensible, but I actually prefer that. It's a bit like a death metal logo in that sense, and I love that. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; There is also a random quote box on the index now! It's randomized each load, but you can also click the refresh button underneath it to get another random quote. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The "brains" on the side are an edit I made of royalty free stock of coral, and the planes on the top and bottom were made in blender. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;[INFO] The links now also now include both the icon and name. Having just the name bothered me before as I felt like it made all the links blend together. They should be easier to find at a glance now.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2&gt;BONUS (WIPS AND MORE)&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;div class="image-row"&gt; &lt;img src="/img/embed/new-index-oct-2024-wip3.png" style="width: 400px"/&gt; &lt;img src="/img/embed/new-index-oct-2024-wip5.png" style="width: 400px"/&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="image-row"&gt; &lt;img src="/img/embed/new-index-oct-2024-wip2.png" style="width: 400px"/&gt; &lt;img src="/img/embed/new-index-oct-2024-wip1.png" style="width: 400px"/&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="image-row"&gt; &lt;img src="/img/embed/new-index-oct-2024-wip4.png"/&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;h1&gt;HOME&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;div class="image-row"&gt; &lt;img src="/img/embed/new-home-oct-2024.png" style="width: 500px"/&gt; &lt;img src="/img/embed/old-home-oct-2024.png" style="width: 500px"/&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;[CAPTION] [FIRST] New home, [SECOND] Old home&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; This one was already live for a bit (at least, an earlier in development version of it), but here's the official log post for it! &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The old version of the home page suffered the same issue of "so focused on mobile friendly that I neglected the desktop experience". Now we got not just one, not just two, but three columns! &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The "placeholder planets" from the index have now been repurposed on this page. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; This columns on the left and right were originally planned out as a separate page, sort of a "diagnostics" page, where you could see stuff like the latest patch notes, the latest log entry, and site statistics. But then I realized that I could just put that information on the home page. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; I love the look and feel of a "BIOS" layout, and decided to take inspiration from that for the layout of the home page. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The "dials" on the sides of the old index have been repurposed to fill the space around the columns. I made that asset in blender. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; We also have a "roadmap" so I can share my plans for the site, and an "artifacts" page! This is where I'll put fun stuff like buttons and stamps! I'm so happy to finally have a place for something like that. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Oh, and I almost forgot to mention the cursor (for when you hover over the planets)! I'm so pleased with how it came out. You can't see it in these screenshots, but if you're on desktop, you can visit the home page right now and see for yourself. :&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; (Speaking of cursors, there's also a new site wide cursor. It's a bit subtle, but it's there! Hehe!) &lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2&gt;BONUS (WIPS AND MORE)&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;div class="image-row"&gt; &lt;img src="/img/embed/new-home-oct-2024-wip1.png"/&gt; &lt;img src="/img/embed/new-home-oct-2024-wip2.png"/&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;img src="/img/embed/new-home-oct-2024-wip3.png"/&gt; &lt;h1&gt;MOBILE&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;div class="image-row"&gt; &lt;img src="/img/embed/new-index-mobile.png"/&gt; &lt;img src="/img/embed/new-home-mobile.png"/&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;[CAPTION] [FIRST] Mobile version of index, [SECOND] Mobile version of home &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; If you're wondering, "are these mobile friendly?", the answer is yes. Yes they are. No matter how complex I make my pages, I want to make sure this site is as mobile friendly as I possibly can, without sacrificing any personality. Because I am an abnormality that actually enjoys trying to make pages mobile friendly. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Due to having a more complex layout, making these pages mobile friendly is also more complex. And there's more than just mobile to consider; there's a lot of different screens in the world of computers! I need to make sure I can account for different window sizes too. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Most of that is easily accomplished automatically since a lot of their widths and heights are based on the window size already, but then we get into issues where the width is so small there's no way the page could be split in three, or something like that. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Both the index and the home layouts rearrange themselves into a single column for smaller screens, and &lt;i&gt;most&lt;/i&gt; of this is pure CSS. It's mostly a matter of making absolute positioned elements into blocks, and containers that originally displayed stuff in rows to instead display stuff in columns. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;[INFO] The planets look complicated, but it's basically the same process! Change their positioning to no longer be absolute, and then have the container that contains them to rearrange them into a nice grid. The planets are a bit of a special case though as I do actually scale them in javascript (to support varying window sizes), but that's a different story.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr/&gt; &lt;p&gt;And that's all I have to share for you today! Until next time...&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Welcome to my world,&lt;br/&gt;Espy&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://espy.world/log/2024/oct/Index%20and%20Home%20Revamp%21.html" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2024-10-25T17:22:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2024-10-25T17:22:00-07:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>espimyte</name>
    </author>
    <category term="art"/>
	<category term="code"/>
	<category term="site"/>
</entry>

<entry>
    <id>https://espy.world/log/2024/oct/The%20Profile%20of%20CinderallaFan39.html</id>
    <title>The Profile of CinderallaFan39</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Greetings! I come to you today with something interesting.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; I was asked by &lt;a href="https://www.pengosolvent.com/"&gt;PengoSolvent&lt;/a&gt; to create a forum mockup for his comic. I did my best to resemble the “old web forum” style given screenshots of old web forums to reference, and I also dug into my memory and experience of old web forums. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You may view the page &lt;a href="/CinderallaFan39.html"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;img src="/img/embed/cinderallafan39-screenshot.png"/&gt; &lt;p&gt;[CAPTION] A screenshot of a mockup of CinderallaFan39's profile page. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Notable parts of old web forum design that I tried to include:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;a love of gradients&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;a love of borders that make certain elements look 3D&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;a love of box shadows&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;muted colors&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;forum signatures&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;fun statistics&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;blue and underlined hyperlinks&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; design that &lt;i&gt;doesn't&lt;/i&gt; consider mobile devices (they weren't big for the web back then!) &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt; The comic that features this page is linked below. I encourage you to check it out! &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.pengosolvent.com/27-hour-comic-2024.html"&gt;https://www.pengosolvent.com/27-hour-comic-2024.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;May there be miracles in your world,&lt;br/&gt;Espy&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://espy.world/log/2024/oct/The%20Profile%20of%20CinderallaFan39.html" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2024-10-22T23:40:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2024-10-22T23:40:00-07:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>espimyte</name>
    </author>
    <category term="art"/>
	<category term="code"/>
</entry>

<entry>
    <id>https://espy.world/log/2024/oct/Changes%20to%20RSS%20on%20the%20site.html</id>
    <title>Changes to RSS on the site</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt; Greetings. I have been working these past few days on some changes to my log (AKA blog) and the RSS feed. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The notable changes are listed below:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt; The feed is now an Atom feed, rather than an RSS feed. &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt; I'm still going to refer to this as an RSS feed, since that seems to be customary on the web at present day. &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; Everything should still functionally be the same. RSS feed readers should still work, and so on. &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; Tags have been implemented. &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt; I'm not exactly sure how filtering works for feed readers, but I believe this change makes it possible. &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; Navigation buttons added. You may now quickly access the previous and next blog entries of the one you are currently reading. &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Blog posted date now features both date AND time.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; Search query implemented for filters. &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt; Essentially, this means that your filter options (and sort, if I add sorting) are saved in the URL. &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; RSS feed now holds full content of post. &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt; Previously, I had a system where I only added an image and a short description for each post. &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; Now you can read the full post directly from certain feed readers without having to go to the link, if your feed reader supports that. &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; Blog entries are now automatically generated as static HTML. &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt; This is a huge timesaver for me as a programmer, since I only have to make changes to a template to have those changes apply to all log entries, instead of having to make those changes on each individual log entry. &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; This also affects the URL of the blog entries. They will now match the title. &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; This also saves time for site visitors. &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt; Before, I had each blog entry page fetch data from &lt;code&gt;.json&lt;/code&gt; files on my site to populate elements such as the title, date, tags, and navigation links on each load. &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; This made the blog entry pages dynamic. However, since their content only changes when I update the site, it's rather unnecessary. &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; The consequence of dynamically populating the page is a slight delay in load time. For me, this is probably less than a second, and maybe longer for other users. Even at just half a second, it was enough to be noticeable, and enough to bother me. &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; For the computer savvy, I've basically cut down on the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Time_complexity"&gt;time complexity&lt;/a&gt; of the site. &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt; With dynamic pages, the time complexity is &lt;code&gt;O(n)&lt;/code&gt; (processing time accumulates at each visit). &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; By automatically generating static HTML at each update, the time complexity has been cut down to &lt;code&gt;O(1)&lt;/code&gt; (processing only occurs when I generate the pages, and no more after that since I only need to generate them once). &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt; In future news, I have a lot planned for this site's future, and you may have already noticed a revamp for the home page. There's more to revamp, and when I feel satisfied, I'll make a dedicated blog post for that as well. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;If you're reading this from your feed reader: Hi!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Have a great evening,&lt;br/&gt;Espy&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://espy.world/log/2024/oct/Changes%20to%20RSS%20on%20the%20site.html" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2024-10-15T20:40:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2024-10-15T20:40:00-07:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>espimyte</name>
    </author>
    <category term="site"/>
	<category term="code"/>
</entry>

<entry>
    <id>https://espy.world/log/2024/oct/GIGAPHONE%202024.html</id>
    <title>GIGAPHONE 2024</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt; At last, my first art update since the beginning of setting up this log! &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; I was part of a massive art telephone game hosted by the lovely &lt;a href="https://ascalaphid.com"&gt;ascalaphid&lt;/a&gt; that lasted for about 14 months, with 72 artists involved! (I am artist 63/72!) &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Behold, my finished piece!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;img src="/img/embed/gigaphone-2024.png" style="width: 800px"/&gt; &lt;p&gt; Tasted a bit of a 'wtf' spice when I received the piece I was going to work off. I decided to triple that spice and send it to the next person. Heheheh. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; You may behold the whole thing here:&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="https://ascalaphid.com/telephone/telephone24"&gt;ART TELEPHONE 2024&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Everyone did absolutely wonderful. I'm honored to have been a part of this massive collaboration! &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Catch ya later,&lt;br/&gt;Espy&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://espy.world/log/2024/oct/GIGAPHONE%202024.html" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2024-10-14T14:44:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2024-10-14T14:44:00-07:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>espimyte</name>
    </author>
    <category term="art"/>
	<category term="telephone"/>
</entry>

<entry>
    <id>https://espy.world/log/2024/oct/Pumpkin%20Soup%20for%20His%20Birthday.html</id>
    <title>Pumpkin Soup for His Birthday</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt; Yesterday was my partner's birthday. He requested soup! Together, we picked a soup that we thought would be fun to make, and one he hadn't tried before. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The soup in question was pumpkin soup! Ideal for the season!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;img src="/img/embed/canh-bi-do.jpg"/&gt; &lt;p&gt;[CAPTION] The soup we made! (Vietnamese Pumpkin Soup AKA Canh Bí Đỏ) &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; This soup in particular is memorable to me due to the interestingly unique taste it had, while simultaneously being light in flavor. A perfect comfort soup, in my opinion. The pumpkin/squash in this soup is rather tender, so it's great for when you want to eat something solid, but can't bite down very hard. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The ingredients in this that I wanted to include specifically because it mimicked the soup I had as a child was the inclusion of the minced pork and black pepper. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; I am surprised at how easy it was to make. I'd love to make this again someday. I am glad to be able to share such a memorable soup with someone else who I care deeply about! &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;May you have wondrous soup in your future,&lt;br/&gt;Espy&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="addendum"&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;b&gt;P.S.&lt;/b&gt; Someone told me that this soup looks like it would go good with tofu! I should try that someday...I think it would go great with cabbage too! &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://espy.world/log/2024/oct/Pumpkin%20Soup%20for%20His%20Birthday.html" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2024-10-10T18:28:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2024-10-10T18:28:00-07:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>espimyte</name>
    </author>
    <category term="thoughts"/>
	<category term="food"/>
</entry>

<entry>
    <id>https://espy.world/log/2024/oct/A%20Constructed%20Espeon.html</id>
    <title>A Constructed Espeon</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt; I had completely forgotten that I ordered this Espeon. I've known about it for a while but it was so low priority due to how easily I could obtain it. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; But I have them now, and as such it is my mission to introduce them! &lt;/p&gt; &lt;h1&gt;Espeon MEGA CONSTRUX&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt; 'MEGA CONSTRUX' is some sort of toy brand for building things out of blocks. You may already be familiar with this sort of toy, though typically the most popular one is called 'LEGO'. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The MEGA CONSTRUX brand released a set of construxs for all the eeveelutions, Espeon included. To obtain the Espeon construx, you could either get the entire eeveelution set, or a set with both Umbreon and Espeon. I settled for the latter. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;img src="/img/embed/espeon-umbreon-construx-box.png" style="width: 400px"/&gt; &lt;p&gt;[CAPTION] Umbreon &amp; Espeon Mega Construx Box&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The Umbreon and Espeon set comes with this little scene of grass and a rotating sun/moon. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Here it is, fully constructed!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;img src="/img/embed/espeon-n-umbreon-construx.png" style="width: 400px"/&gt; &lt;p&gt;[CAPTION] Umbreon &amp; Espeon Mega Construx&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Of course, since I only care for the Espeon, the Umbreon will instead be gifted to my partner, who also assisted me in constructing this set. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;img src="/img/espeon/espeon_mega_construx.png" style="width: 400px"/&gt; &lt;p&gt;[CAPTION] &lt;s&gt;Umbreon &amp;amp;&lt;/s&gt; Espeon Mega Construx&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Below is a GIF I created showcasing the process of creating this construx. Enjoy! &lt;/p&gt; &lt;img src="/img/embed/espeon-construx.gif" style="margin-bottom: 10px"/&gt; &lt;p&gt;See you next Espeon,&lt;br/&gt;Espy&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://espy.world/log/2024/oct/A%20Constructed%20Espeon.html" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2024-10-08T17:12:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2024-10-08T17:12:00-07:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>espimyte</name>
    </author>
    <category term="espeon"/>
</entry>

<entry>
    <id>https://espy.world/log/2024/oct/Dynamically%20Sized%20Grid.html</id>
    <title>Dynamically Sized Grid</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt; Greetings. In this post, I write about coding a 'dynamically sized grid' for my website. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; I have just added sorts and filters to my &lt;a href="/espeon.html"&gt;espeon collection&lt;/a&gt; page, and in addition, I've implemented a "dynamically sized grid", so to speak. It was necessary for the update for sorts and filters, as I wanted to allow users to see the entirety of the cards, but also wanted a very evenly spaced grid. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; A statically sized grid worked fine before, as you couldn't view both TCG cards and non-TCG items at the same time. But once images of all sorts of different sizes mix, trying to create a nice grid that efficiently takes up all the space on the screen AND that lets you view the entirety of each image becomes difficult. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Essentially, I wanted something like this. Something similar to the way deviantArt displays gallery images as of writing. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;img src="/img/embed/deviantart-grid-screenshot.png"/&gt; &lt;p&gt;[CAPTION] Screenshot of my deviantArt gallery, showcasing the arrangement of images that I am trying to achieve. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; In the above, each of the images are arranged neatly, taking up the entirety of the available width, without having to crop out any of the images. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; I had no intention to make a blog post about this, however, the process of making a dynamic grid was quite interesting. My search online yielded very little actionable results. I'm sure there's a way to do this in pure CSS, but I do not know how. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; A lot of what I write about code isn't exactly formatted for learning (though I try where I can). Though I am determined to make sure what I learned (which may not really be all that valuable) does not go unsaid. Consider this more as personal documentation. With that said, let's begin. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;h1&gt;THE LOGIC BEHIND A DYNAMICALLY SIZED GRID&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt;Here's what we need:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;We must support images of ANY size.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; We must display images in their original aspect ratio, without cropping. &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;We must exactly fill the width of the entire grid.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;The height of each image in a row must be the same.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt; Due to the nature of what we are trying to accomplish, there is one thing we will have to compromise on, and that is the height of each row. It will vary a bit. Though I personally don't mind. As long as the heights of each image in the row are all the same, I'm content. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2&gt;STEP 1: FILLING A ROW&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt; First of all, let's figure out how to fill a row with differently sized images and fill a certain width. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Take these 3 image sizes.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;img class="reader-only" src="/img/embed/dynamic-squares-1.png"/&gt; &lt;p&gt;We've got a square image, a wide image, and a tall image!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; (If you're viewing this on mobile, the sizes won't be accurate but hopefully their aspect ratio is the same.) &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; How are we going to fit this all in a row with the same height AND same aspect ratio? &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The first step is to &lt;b&gt;normalize&lt;/b&gt; the sizes of each image to a certain height. Basically, we're going to resize them to a certain height while maintaining the aspect ratio. The goal is to calculate the new width of each image to this new height. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; I'm going to normalize them to the height of &lt;code&gt;100px&lt;/code&gt; as an example. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3&gt;HOW TO NORMALIZE&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Real quick. Here's the formula.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="code-block"&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;w = current width&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;h = current height&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;dw = desired width&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;dh = desired height&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;dh/h * w = dw&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt; With this, the sizes of each of the images (in px) normalized are: &lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Square - 100w x 100h&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Wide - 200w x 100h&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Tall - 60w x 100h&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;img class="reader-only" src="/img/embed/dynamic-squares-2.png"/&gt; &lt;p&gt; There we go! We can use this information to fill up a specified width with images. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Let's fill a row of width &lt;code&gt;300px&lt;/code&gt; with these squares.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; To do this, we need to determine the height that would let us fill the width with the image sizes we currently have, then resize the images to that height. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The first thing we need is the heights of each of the images normalized to any height, which we've already done! (In the code, I've normalized them to a height of &lt;code&gt;1px&lt;/code&gt;, but any height will do). &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The next step is to sum up each of the normalized widths.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="code-block"&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;100px + 200px + 60px = 360px&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt; This is the total width of all our squares normalized to a height of 100px! &lt;/p&gt; &lt;img class="reader-only" src="/img/embed/dynamic-squares-3.png"/&gt; &lt;p&gt; All our images combined gives us one BIG rectangle of 360px by 100px size! &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; And all we have to do now, is normalize &lt;b&gt;that&lt;/b&gt; to a width of 300px. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; This is the same formula as before, but trying to find the height instead of the width. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="code-block"&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;dw/w * h = dh&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;(300px/360px) * 100px = ~83px&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt; And there we go! If we want to fill a width of 300px with these squares, we need a height of 83px. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Here's the squares normalized to a height of 83px, creating a row that is 300px wide and 83px tall. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;img class="reader-only" src="/img/embed/dynamic-squares-4.png"/&gt; &lt;h2&gt;STEP 2: DETERMINING HOW MANY IMAGES IN A ROW&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt; The previous step of normalizing heights for a row can be done for pretty much any amount of images of any size. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; But we're not trying to create a row, we're trying to create a whole grid! &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;So where do we stop?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Here's something to note: The more images in a row, the wider the row, and the smaller the row height. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The system I came up with uses what I call a "size goal".&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; In other words, each time an image is added to the row, I calculate the resulting height of the row to the grid width. As images get added, the resulting height becomes smaller and smaller. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Once the height of the row is no longer above the size goal, I start adding images to the next row. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2&gt;STEP 3: THE WHOLE PROCESS&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt; I will demonstrate an example with the following image sizes, grid width, and height size goal. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The desired width of the grid is &lt;code&gt;300px&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The height size goal is &lt;code&gt;150px&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;img class="reader-only" src="/img/embed/dynamic-squares-5.png"/&gt; &lt;p&gt; First, let's get all of the widths normalized to a height of 100px. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;img class="reader-only" src="/img/embed/dynamic-squares-6.png"/&gt; &lt;p&gt; Next, we'll slowly add images into the row and sizing them until they fit the width, and stopping once the height goes below the size goal. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="code-block"&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;dw/w * h = dh&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;(300px/(100px)) * 100px = 300px&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;img class="reader-only" src="/img/embed/dynamic-squares-7.png"/&gt; &lt;p&gt; The height of this row is &lt;code&gt;300px&lt;/code&gt;, which is higher than our size goal of &lt;code&gt;150px&lt;/code&gt;. This row is far too tall with just a single image! Let's add another image to the row. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="code-block"&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;dw/w * h = dh&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;(300px/(100px+200px)) * 100px = 100px&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;img class="reader-only" src="/img/embed/dynamic-squares-8.png"/&gt; &lt;p&gt; Because the height of this row is below our size goal of &lt;code&gt;110px&lt;/code&gt;, we're finished with this row! Now we will continue with the rest of the images on the next row. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="code-block"&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;dw/w * h = dh&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;(300px/(60px)) * 100px = 500px&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;img class="reader-only" src="/img/embed/dynamic-squares-9.png"/&gt; &lt;p&gt; Just like before, the height of this row, &lt;code&gt;500px&lt;/code&gt;, far surpasses our size goal of &lt;code&gt;150px&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="code-block"&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;dw/w * h = dh&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;(300px/(60px+114px)) * 100px = 172px&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;img class="reader-only" src="/img/embed/dynamic-squares-10.png"/&gt; &lt;p&gt; The height of this row, &lt;code&gt;172px&lt;/code&gt;, is still above our height goal of &lt;code&gt;150px&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="code-block"&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;dw/w * h = dh&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;(300px/(60px+114px+76px)) * 100px = 120px&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;img class="reader-only" src="/img/embed/dynamic-squares-11.png"/&gt; &lt;p&gt; Because this last row has a height (&lt;code&gt;120px&lt;/code&gt;) that's below our current size goal of &lt;code&gt;150px&lt;/code&gt;, this row is finished! &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; And since we've finished adding all of the images, we are done with building our dynamically sized grid! (^_^)b &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; If you are also stuck on this problem, I hope that this provides, at the very least, a framework to build your dynamically sized grid on. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; If you want to see this sort of dynamically sized grid in action, you can do so at my &lt;a href="/espeon.html"&gt;espeon collection page&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Dynamically,&lt;br/&gt;Espy&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://espy.world/log/2024/oct/Dynamically%20Sized%20Grid.html" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2024-10-07T15:01:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2024-10-07T15:01:00-07:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>espimyte</name>
    </author>
    <category term="site"/>
	<category term="code"/>
</entry>

<entry>
    <id>https://espy.world/log/2024/oct/My%20Espeon%20Collection.html</id>
    <title>My Espeon Collection</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Espeon is my favorite pokémon, and the origin of my namesake.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; It all started with my first pokémon game, 'Pokémon XD: Gale of Darkness'. The starter pokémon for that game is an Eevee, and I ended up evolving it into an Espeon. It became my favorite pokémon ever since. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;img src="/img/embed/espeon-xd-screenshot.png"/&gt; &lt;p&gt;[CAPTION] A screenshot of Espeon in "Pokémon XD: Gale of Darkness" &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; And one may think: "Ah, someone that likes Espeon this much, they must have a lot of Espeon merch lying around"! However, such was not the case. Back then, at least. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; At some point I decided I needed to have at least one Espeon in my posession, so I got something. And during that process, I started looking more into the Espeon merch of the world. There's a LOT of Espeons, and it's so fascinating to see all the stuff they make. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; I especially love any interesting or weird Espeon merch out there. Most of it is plushies and figures, but sometimes you get something like a Mamezara plate, a watch, a sticker that came free with special edition ramen, chopsticks, perfume, or even a skateboard. (That skateboard is one of my favorite things I've ever owned.) &lt;/p&gt; &lt;img src="/img/espeon/espeon_plate.jpg" style="width: 400px"/&gt; &lt;p&gt;[CAPTION] A Mamezara plate featuring Espeon.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; And then there's cards! Cards have an additional fun aspect of trying to collect the same card in different languages. Cards are much easier to collect and store in my experience. Although most cards are cheaper than other merch, if a card is expensive, oh boy is it expensive. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;img src="/img/embed/pop-series-5-espeon.jpg" style="width: 250px"/&gt; &lt;p&gt;[CAPTION] Pop Series 5 Espeon Star, a card that is sometimes sold for over $6000 or more. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; I keep a personal database to keep track of all the Espeons I own, and all the Espeons that I don't. Everytime I think I've found all the Espeons that have ever been made, I find something new. As of writing, I am aware of 564 official Espeon items in the world, and I currently own 158 of them. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Either way, having an Espeon collection...it's so nice, seeing them all together. Looking at them on the shelves, or flipping through my card binder. Seeing other people collect was always so cool, just the awe of seeing so much of something all in once place. I can't believe now I'm one of those collectors. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I hope to keep collecting! It honestly brings me a lot of joy.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;And I hope to share my Espeons with you as well. :)&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; You can view my entire collection &lt;a href="/espeon.html"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Now, I will begin the first update! We have two new Espeons joining the horde today. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;h1&gt;2022 Espeon Wonderland Spinning Scenes Pin&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;img src="/img/espeon/2022_Espeon_Wonderland_Spinning_Scenes_Pin.jpg" style="width: 500px"/&gt; &lt;p&gt; This is a pin with a rotating element to it! The foliage can be rotated to make different scenes! In the images, you can see the two possible scenes. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The first one looks quite like spring, with it's pink colors, and you can make out Ho-Oh in the background. I'm sure the butterflies in the image are also pokémon; Butterfree, if I had to guess. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The second scene, which I've shown in the top right, has the foliage acting as leaves for a tree! You can see an Oddish to the left and a Cherrim in its sunshine form on the right. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;h1&gt;2023 Espeon Timeless Friends Card Sleeves&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;img src="/img/espeon/2023_Espeon_Timeless_Friends_Card_Sleeves.jpg" style="width: 500px"/&gt; &lt;p&gt; This is part of a "Timeless Friends" series for the pokémon TCG. Some of the other stuff made for this series included a playmat, card divider, and a deck box. They featured Umbreon with Murkrow, and Espeon with Celebi. I have the other Espeon related parts of the "Timeless Friends" set, and the card sleeves were the last one I needed; hooray! &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; An important note: I am only interested in seeing Espeon, so I do not collect things that, for example, feature all of the eeveelutions. It's fine if other pokemon are involved, but I'm only interested in items that feature Espeon as the core focus on the item. That is my personal rule! &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; That's it! Thanks for reading! I am not currently actively collecting Espeons at the moment, but when the time comes, I look forward to sharing them with you. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;See you next Espeon,&lt;br/&gt;Espy&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://espy.world/log/2024/oct/My%20Espeon%20Collection.html" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2024-10-01T09:31:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2024-10-01T09:31:00-07:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>espimyte</name>
    </author>
    <category term="espeon"/>
	<category term="thoughts"/>
</entry>

<entry>
    <id>https://espy.world/log/2024/sep/The%20lab%20is%20open..html</id>
    <title>The lab is open.</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've organized all my code-related stuff into one place!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can check out the lab &lt;a href="/lab.html"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; It has replaced the area previously known as "play". Do not worry. There is still room for "play" in the machines. Though I do not promise safety! Try not to lose a limb or two. HAHA! &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; I'm going to go over each of the current entities in the lab, as of writing. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr/&gt; &lt;h2&gt;EYECRYPT&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;div class="img-container"&gt; &lt;img src="/img/eyecrypt/eyecrypt-icon.png"/&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt; I've already talked about this one in length in a previous blog post, but I'll give a short summary here. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; This is, essentially, an encryption visualizer! Feel free to experiment with it, play with it, or use it for your own purposes! &lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2&gt;Carpet Snake&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;div class="img-container"&gt; &lt;img src="/img/snake.png"/&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt; A very simple game I made in 2021 when I was bored (also cuz I wanted to test making a game that could be played in browser). &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; It's just snake but with more varied looking body parts than the typical snake game. I found it mesmerizing to watch the movement of the snake when I played snake before, watching as there suddenly became more snake than not snake in the world as the game progressed. So this is the story of a snake in a colorless world that fills the world with color by becoming so large it envelopes the world entirely with its colorful body. Designing their patterns was quite soothing. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Not the first game I've made but the first game I've shared to the public eye because every other game I've made I'm too shy to share. Hopefully that will change one day. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2&gt;Pixel Grid&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;div class="img-container"&gt; &lt;img src="/img/mimitchi.png"/&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt; A random thing I made when I was bored. This is just an interactable pixel grid. Inspired by (and references) the code of the many "css crimes" on cohost that played around with the 'details/summary' element. It does not use any javascript at all. Enjoy. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2&gt;Izzy&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;div class="img-container"&gt; &lt;img src="/img/izzy-icon.png"/&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt; Izzy got lost and ended up here in the lab. We're keeping him in one of our test tubes. Why not hear what he has to say? &lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2&gt;bits&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt; Just a thing that I wrote specifically for one person so that they could perhaps understand what "bits" in images were a little bit more. It's in the lab cuz I don't know where else to put it. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr/&gt; &lt;p&gt;That's it! Enjoy the lab.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Keep experimenting,&lt;br/&gt;Espy&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="addendum"&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;b&gt;P.S.&lt;/b&gt; Did you know that the blog supports comments now? Courtesy of &lt;a href="https://virtualobserver.moe/"&gt;virtualobserver&lt;/a&gt;. Since this blog doesn't use any third party services, that means everything down to writing new blog posts and generating the RSS feed has to be done by myself. This also includes comments. I searched long and hard for a simple comments section I could integrate into my neocities that was also fully customizable and finally found it. Check it out &lt;a href="https://virtualobserver.moe/ayano/comment-widget"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Feel free to leave a comment! I don't even know if anyone reads these posts, haha. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://espy.world/log/2024/sep/The%20lab%20is%20open..html" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2024-09-27T07:54:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2024-09-27T07:54:00-07:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>espimyte</name>
    </author>
    <category term="site"/>
</entry>

<entry>
    <id>https://espy.world/log/2024/sep/Aiding%20site%20development%20with%20scripting.html</id>
    <title>Aiding site development with scripting</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt; In this post, I’m going to talk about some scripts I recently developed to make site development easier, including a custom RSS feed generator and an image optimizer! &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;[INFO] &lt;b&gt;Fun Fact:&lt;/b&gt; Did you know the site is mobile friendly? (Well, at least it should be. Hopefully!)&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; I really &lt;b&gt;really&lt;/b&gt; like working on the site. I cannot stress this enough. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; It’s just incredible. It feels great to code for myself, to code for my own space on the web. I can do whatever I want! You can do whatever you want! &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; And it’s just fun! And surprisingly, not frustrating. I’ve grown a lot as a coder since I first started doing HTML and CSS when I was younger. For one, I’m using an interface that lets me preview the site as I make changes live! No longer am I having to manually check how something looks and then going back to code. In addition, I also have two monitors now. Which means no more switching between windows. A luxury that has afforded me a lot of peace. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Also I no longer have a crappy chair.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; I've been working on scripts to help with site development, and all of this stuff makes development feel so much easier. If you can, I highly encourage you to change your environment to the best of your ability. Not just physically (though that matters too), but digitally as well! If you’re tired of all these Sisyphean tasks working on a website throws your way, I guarantee there’s an easier way with the magic of code. Either someone online has made a tool for it, or you can make your own tools! &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The ability to make your own tools is extremely powerful. If no one else will make it, you can. You absolutely can. You don’t have to wait for anyone. (Plus it's a great learning experience.) &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Your comfort is valuable, especially in spaces you exist in and work in often. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;h1&gt;THE SCRIPTS&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt; Let me show you what site development was like before writing these scripts. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;img src="/img/embed/script-diagram-1.png"/&gt; &lt;p&gt; As seen in this diagram, everytime I make changes to the site, I have to do 4 things. I want to only do 1 thing! Well, not to worry, this is possible with the magic of scripts. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; I’m going to talk about the recent scripts I recently developed to make site development easier. There will be some technical jargon. I will attempt to communicate this in a way so that those that are not familiar with the language of machines may still be able to understand to the best of my ability. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Here are the scripts that I've made!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Custom RSS Generator&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Image Optimizer&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Site Updater&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;Let's go through them one by one.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2&gt;SITE UPDATER&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt; I use &lt;code&gt;github&lt;/code&gt; as source control. If you're not familiar with github or source control here's a quick summary. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Source control is something that allows me to keep track of and manage changes to my code, as well as revert my site to a previous state in case I fuck something up. Github is a form of source control. When I make changes to my site, I "push" (aka upload) it to the associated github repository that I made for the site. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Before writing this script, site development went like this.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ol&gt; &lt;li&gt;I code stuff for the site.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;I push the changes the github repository.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;I manually update the site with whatever I changed.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ol&gt; &lt;p&gt; This results in me having to update two things at once (github and neocities), and I'd rather not do that. Let's find a way to not do that! &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; This site is built on neocities, and neocities has graciously provided a &lt;code&gt;API&lt;/code&gt;! API stands for application programming interface. Essentially, this allows me to make changes to my site by directly sending a signal to neocities using code or whatnot, instead of having to log onto neocities and uploading the files myself using the web browser. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; I'm going to be accessing the neocities API using the neocities &lt;code&gt;CLI&lt;/code&gt; (command line interface). The CLI lets me use terminal commands to use the API. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The following is an example of a terminal command I could run using the neocities CLI. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;neocities upload index.html&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Now what this does is it sends a signal to the neocities API that says "Hey! I have this file called &lt;code&gt;index.html&lt;/code&gt;, please upload this to the server." &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The request starts at the user, and goes all the way to the site.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can think of the chain of the request like this.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;code&gt;User -&gt; Neocities CLI -&gt; Neocities API -&gt; Neocities Site&lt;/code&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; And get this. The user doesn't have to be a person! It can also be a computer. This is key in how we can automate updating the site. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; How can we connect github to neocities, so that when I update the version of the site on the github repository, the site will also update? &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; As of writing, neocities provides &lt;a href="https://neocities.org/cli"&gt;instructions&lt;/a&gt; of how to invoke the CLI when you use github. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;img src="/img/embed/clihook-instructions.png"/&gt; &lt;p&gt;[CAPTION] A screenshot of the instructions on the neocities site. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; This is called a "git hook", called as such because you can "hook" something up to run alongside actions associated with your github. Using this, now instead of manually updating your site, when you push changes to your repository, your site gets updated automatically! &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Here's a diagram of what's happening!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;img src="/img/embed/script-diagram-2.png"/&gt; &lt;p&gt;[CAPTION] A diagram showing how the git hook works.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Just one problem.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The hook that neocities provides uploads the ENTIRE site with every push. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; To be clear, this hook &lt;b&gt;works&lt;/b&gt;! And probably works perfectly fine for most sites and most users. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;But it does...take a while…&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; And when the site grows bigger and bigger, it’s going to take longer and longer. Long enough that it would be faster for me to just manually update the site. Which is what I was trying to avoid doing in the first place! &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; If only the hook would only upload changed files, instead of the entire site. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Let's make our own hook that does just that! We'll still be using the neocities CLI, but this time, we're going to tell the CLI &lt;b&gt;exactly&lt;/b&gt; what we want to upload, instead of just letting the CLI reupload the entire site each time. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;How do we know what changed?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This information is already provided to us with github!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;img src="/img/embed/github-screenshot.png"/&gt; &lt;p&gt;[CAPTION] A screenshot of github desktop showing changes to the site. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;How do we pass this along to the neocities CLI?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Let's write a script! The script can be written in basically any language. As long as your computer can run it, it's valid. I personally wrote mine in "python". &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Right now, the hook neocities provides uses the "push" command from the CLI, which pushes the entire site to neocities. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; However, the CLI also provides the upload and delete commands, which allow us to upload/delete individual files on our site. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Using the information we have from github, we can tell neocities what to do with the changes! &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; First of all, we need to get the changes. We as "human" users can see what changed, but how can we pass this information to the CLI? &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; We can use this command! You can see a breakdown of this command &lt;a href="https://git-scm.com/docs/git-diff"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, if you're curious. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;git diff --stat --cached --name-status origin/main&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Here's what we see when we run the command.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;img src="/img/embed/git-diff-output-screenshot.png"/&gt; &lt;p&gt;[INFO] 'Github' and 'git' are two different things! A common misconception.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Let’s break down what we’re seeing.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td&gt;File added.&lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;td&gt;D&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td&gt;File deleted.&lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;td&gt;M&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td&gt;File modified.&lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;td&gt;R&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td&gt;File renamed.&lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;/table&gt; &lt;p&gt;[INFO] The number after R indicates the file's "score", which is the similarity between the source file and the target file. R100 in this case means the action has a score of 100, which means that the files have a 100% similarity with each other (because they're the same).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Now that we have a list of every change we've made, we need to tell neocities what to do with each of these changes. Let’s go through them one by one. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="note"&gt; You may be wondering where "moved" files come into play here. We'll get to that! &lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3&gt;Handling added files&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt; This is simple enough. Simple upload the file using the neocities CLI's upload command. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style="margin-bottom: 0"&gt;Example:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style="margin-top: 0"&gt; &lt;code&gt;neocities upload -d img img/microscopic-merse.png&lt;/code&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3&gt;Handling deleted files&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt; Another simple action. Simple delete the file using the neocities CLI's delete command. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style="margin-bottom: 0"&gt;Example:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style="margin-top: 0"&gt; &lt;code&gt;neocities delete img/butterfly.png&lt;/code&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3&gt;Handling modified files&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt; When you upload a file to neocities, if that file already exists, it will replace that file. As such, we can simply just upload the modified file to the site. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style="margin-bottom: 0"&gt;Example:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style="margin-top: 0"&gt;&lt;code&gt;neocities upload index.html&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;[INFO] Neocities won't upload the file if it thinks they're the same (data wise)! I've run into issues with a file being changed, but neocities refusing to upload it because it thinks an identical file already exists on the server. I've primarily observed this with image files. To resolve this, I delete the file and THEN upload the file if I detect the file is an image.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3&gt;Handling "renamed" files&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt; This one is interesting. Although this status applies to renamed files, this status can also occur when you move a file. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Why does this happen? Well, computers don't really see files as just their names. They see files as their name AND their path. When a file is moved, they see something like this. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;izzy.html -&gt; alt/izzy.html&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Which looks just like a file being renamed.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; How do we handle this? There’s no “move” or “rename” command in neocities. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;It's actually quite simple!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ol&gt; &lt;li&gt;Upload the file in the new location.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Remove the "old" file in the original location.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ol&gt; &lt;p&gt; This basically produces the same result as moving/renaming the file. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt; And there we have it! These are the ingredients we need to write a script that will upload only changed files to the site whenever we update our github repository. Once the script is done, we simply replace the original neocities hook provided to us to use it. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The following is pseudocode that shows the base logic of the script. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="code-block"&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;for each change:&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style="text-indent: 1em"&gt;&lt;code&gt;if status is 'A':&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style="text-indent: 2em"&gt;&lt;code&gt;upload_file(path)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style="text-indent: 1em"&gt;&lt;code&gt;else if status is 'D':&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style="text-indent: 2em"&gt;&lt;code&gt;delete_file(path)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style="text-indent: 1em"&gt;&lt;code&gt;else if status is 'M':&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style="text-indent: 2em"&gt;&lt;code&gt;upload_file(path)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style="text-indent: 1em"&gt;&lt;code&gt;else if status is 'R':&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style="text-indent: 2em"&gt;&lt;code&gt;upload_file(new_path)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style="text-indent: 2em"&gt;&lt;code&gt;delete_file(old_path)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;h2&gt;Custom RSS Generator&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt; The acronym of RSS has been quite malleable over the years! First it was "RDF Site Summary", but then they stopped using RDF, so it became "Rich Site Summary". Some people have taken to calling it "Really Simple Syndication". And as the name implies, it's really simple. At least, simple in relation to all the other machine stuff you may read about. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; All you need to make an RSS feed is to have a file on your site in an RSS format (typically as a &lt;code&gt;.xml&lt;/code&gt; file). And all you need to read RSS blogs is an RSS reader with the links to those files on other people's websites. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; As people update their blogs, the files on their website update too, and the people subscribed to those feeds will get the update. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Here's the (basic) format of an RSS file.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="code-block"&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;[HEADER]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style="text-indent: 1em"&gt;&lt;code&gt;[ITEM 1]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style="text-indent: 1em"&gt;&lt;code&gt;[ITEM 2]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style="text-indent: 1em"&gt;&lt;code&gt;[ITEM 3]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style="text-indent: 1em"&gt;&lt;code&gt;[...]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;[HEADER END]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt; Without an RSS generator, everytime I make a new blog post, I'll have to update the feed manually. But we don't have to live that way. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; There are a lot of RSS generators online, but I was too lazy to figure any of them out and decided to just make one myself. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; To do this, we’ll need the data from the blog entries. We don’t need the whole post, just a few things: &lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Link to blog entry&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Title of blog entry&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Date of blog entry&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;And optionally:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Image to attach to blog entry.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Description of blog entry.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt; The optional parameters are just going to be what shows up on people's feeds before they actually click on the link. I could auto-generate these, but I honestly prefer to set it myself. If you're making your own custom RSS generator, you can do whatever you want. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; When I first started writing this script, the data was already on the website. Hardcoded into a javascript file. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The problem with this data being hardcoded means that I can't really access this data from the script! &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Aw geez.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; If only there was a way we can share data between both my javascript code and the RSS generator script! &lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3&gt;Introducing JSON Files&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt; JSON stands for "JavaScript Object Notation". (I am now noticing that there are a lot of computer acronyms in this post.) &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; I really fricking love JSON files, because they're so convenient to work with. Almost every programming language can read JSON files in one way or another, and it's a great way to share complex data between all sorts of different applications and programming languages. I find it to be easy to read, so it's not complex to update! &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="note"&gt; I won't be going into detail about JSON files in this post. You can see some examples of JSON files &lt;a href="https://simple.wikipedia.org/wiki/JSON"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Unfortunately, past me did not foresee the use of JSON files, so I ended up having to migrate a lot of hardcoded data to JSON files. I do think it was worth it. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3&gt;BACK TO IT&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Now that all the data has been migrated, we can really begin!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The script is quite simple.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;First, we will provide templates for the script to use.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; We provide a template for both the header of the RSS file, and for each individual item. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;After we do that, here's what we'll have our script do.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ol&gt; &lt;li&gt;Read the data in the JSON file.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Sort each of the entries by date.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; Fill in the item template with the data from one of the entries. &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Repeat with the previous step with each entry.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Insert all the filled out items into the header template.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ol&gt; &lt;p&gt;And huzzah.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; And of course, this goes in the hook too, so it will run automatically each time we update the site. We never have to worry about updating the RSS feed ourselves. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2&gt;Image Optimizer&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt; You may have noticed that on some sites with big images, they take a while to load. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; A lot of sites automatically compress images so that anyone that visits their site won't have to wait for all the images to load. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I'm gonna do this too!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; I will be using another CLI, one known as &lt;a href="https://imagemagick.org/"&gt;ImageMagick&lt;/a&gt; for this. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; By making my own script, I have greater control in how the images are compressed. This way, I can tailor the image optimization to the kind of images I will tend to upload on the site. This gives me the potential to maximize optimization wile also maintaining the quality of the image as best as I can. I can also control what images are compressed, and other variables like the max size of an image file, denote any exceptions, and etcetera. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Here's how the script works:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ol&gt; &lt;li&gt;Check folders (which I specify) for large image files.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; Tell ImageMagick to optimize any image files that are over the limit (specified in the script). &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ol&gt; &lt;p&gt;...That's it!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This too, gets hooked up!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h1&gt;The Result&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt; With all these scripts written and hooked up, here's how site development works now. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;img src="/img/embed/script-diagram-3.png"/&gt; &lt;p&gt;[CAPTION] A diagram showing how the git hook works with all the scripts. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; You may have noticed something awesome. Now instead of having to do 4 things, I only have to do 1 thing, and the scripts take care of the rest! &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The site updater is nice because, since it only uploads what's changed and not the entire site, I can quickly update the site with small changes, without having to wait as long. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The RSS generator runs so fast I don’t need to bother with checking if the log updated, I can just regenerate the feed everytime and it's no issue. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The image optimizer will only take as much time as it needs, since it only needs to optimize each image once, so I don't need to worry about speed for that one too. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; I no longer have to do all these tasks manually, and I can maintain both the source on github and the live site on neocities! &lt;/p&gt; &lt;h1&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt; I really love code because of all the interesting problems it presents, and there's so many ways to solve all these different problems. This site is a growing organism, and still in its infancy to me. These scripts are like its organs to me. To allow these scripts to pump blood like the heart or digest food like the stomach; these functions happen without even thinking, lowering the burden on the consciousness. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; These are the sorts of things that I think automation is really about. Allowing code to take hold of all these tasks that would overwhelm me should I try handling it all by myself, so I can focus on the things that matter to me. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; If you can, I would highly encourage you to make organs of your own. This too, is an act of creation! To me, this is the essence of &lt;b&gt;mad science&lt;/b&gt;. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading,&lt;br/&gt;Espy&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://espy.world/log/2024/sep/Aiding%20site%20development%20with%20scripting.html" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2024-09-23T06:40:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2024-09-23T06:40:00-07:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>espimyte</name>
    </author>
    <category term="site"/>
	<category term="code"/>
</entry>

<entry>
    <id>https://espy.world/log/2024/sep/shout%20out%20to%20food.html</id>
    <title>shout out to food</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt; I wrote a bit about food on my cohost sideblog, starting each of them with &lt;span class="highlight"&gt;“shout out to [food item]"&lt;/span&gt;. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; I didn’t intend to make it a whole thing, but I sort of just kept going. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; I've never really shared a lot of my thoughts on the internet before. And I never felt the itch to, until recently. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; One of the first things I wanted to share with people was meaningful experiences I had with food. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; During my worst and lowest moments, if I could still reach out for something to help me, I could always look forward to food. A good meal. It is a simple source of joy. And some days I felt like I could be happy thinking about the yummy things I could eat in the future. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; It’s interesting though. I actually struggle to eat much. Not only is my metabolism off the charts, I guess my stomach really isn’t that big either. I used to speak a lot of vietnamese but I can't really anymore, cuz assimilation and all that. But that's a story for another time. There is still a phrase that I can utter effortlessly, almost by instinct. &lt;span class="highlight"&gt;(It's also the thing I say whenever people are like "woah, you're vietnamese? say something in vietnamese!")&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="quote"&gt;“Không muốn ăn nữa.”&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Which means &lt;span class="highlight"&gt;“I don’t want to eat anymore.”&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; On the bright side, it means I have plenty of leftovers! Now if only I can eat them all before they go bad... &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; There are some foods that I cannot bear to eat as a result of eating them for too many days in a row. Like…boiled quail eggs, jackfruit, or banana bread. I’d like to enjoy them again though. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="note"&gt; (Why did I eat so much jackfruit and boiled quail eggs? Ask my mom, who either bought them in bulk from the international supermarket or as a gift from her coworkers, who probably were looking for someone to dump all their extra food on.) &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Something that is really fun is sharing food with others. I shared peanut sauce to this person in my class in college and they loved it. Making congee for my partner Slither while we played board games. Goodness, cooking for someone is such a treat. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;img src="/img/embed/saejima-cooking.png"/&gt; &lt;p&gt;[CAPTION] Saejima from the Yakuza series&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Speaking of making food, cooking is really quite fun! I used to be terrified of the kitchen. Something about the heat that emanates from the kitchen appliances while you cook just terrifies me. I’ve recently been trying to cook again. I almost fainted a few times. But now I’m very confident! Not in my cooking skill, mind you, but in not fainting. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; It's nice not to just cook for others, but to also be cooked food by others! I was visiting a friend once and was tired from a long flight, and their roommates shared soup with me. What a nice experience. How kind of them to make soup. How wonderful the taste and the warmth. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="note"&gt; (It was italian wedding soup, if you were wondering.) &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; As you may know, I enjoy new experiences. There is something to attain from the experience of eating both good and bad food. I want to celebrate all of it, not just delicious food, but food that takes you to another dimension of agony as well. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; To be clear, I would prefer to be in agony as little as possible. But if I happen to come across it, I can at least consider it a fond memory for the future. Depends. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; One day, I'd like to design the food of my worlds as well. I like to think about what my characters would eat and their relationship with food. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Below are the archived posts on food that I shared on cohost. Please consume this banquet to your heart’s content. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;details class="bok-choy"&gt; &lt;summary&gt;shout out to bok choy&lt;span&gt; 1/13/2024&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/summary&gt; &lt;p&gt;ADDENDUM&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The very first "shout out"! Inspired by watching a mahjong twitch streamer say "shout out to bok choy"! And I too, wished to put that same sentiment into the world. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/details&gt; &lt;details class="tomatoes"&gt; &lt;summary&gt;shout out to tomatoes&lt;span&gt; 3/15/2024&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/summary&gt; &lt;p&gt; I used to hate tomatoes, but then one day I was given a single slice of tomato to eat. My initial reaction was “are you kidding me” followed by reluctantly taking a bite, only to be hit with the most heavenly taste I ever had in my entire life. I was really shocked, taking a bite out of one of my least favorite foods and it tasting amazing. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; this event reshaped how I viewed food, suddenly the world of food felt far more vast than before, and I felt like a fool to have thought that the experience of the food was defined only by the type of food itself, and not by any other factors. I used to think that if I had like, say, a jackfruit and didn’t like it for example, it meant that I didn’t like jackfruits and all jackfruits were bad. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;but maybe this whole time I’ve never had a good tomato&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/details&gt; &lt;details class="jackfruit"&gt; &lt;summary&gt;shout out to jackfruit&lt;span&gt; 3/16/2024&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/summary&gt; &lt;p&gt; I don’t like jackfruit. I still don’t. but maybe one day the jackfruit from heaven will descend on my doorstep and reshape my worldview. any day now &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;THE JACKFRUIT INCIDENT&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; one day a family member brought home an absurd amount of jackfruit. it was stored in the fridge. the strong odor contaminated everything in the fridge. for days everything tasted like jackfruit. the water tasted like jackfruit. the rice tasted like jackfruit. even the meat tasted like jackfruit. it was torment for the senses, even to those that enjoyed jackfruit. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/details&gt; &lt;details class="lychee"&gt; &lt;summary&gt;shout out to lychee&lt;span&gt; 3/18/2024&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/summary&gt; &lt;p&gt; in particular I want to give a mention to lychee juice. before trying lychee juice, I had only had real lychee. there’s usually a difference between eating a fruit, and then drinking something that tastes like the fruit. strawberry tastes a lot different than strawberry juice; first of all strawberry is solid and juice is liquid. essentially, eating a fruit and drinking fruit juice are different experiences. your brain can tell the difference. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;or so I thought!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; I had quite a reaction when drinking that lychee juice, because it tasted EXACTLY like lychee. not just the taste, but it somehow mimicked the experience of physically eating an actual lychee, the actual TACTILE sensation! for a moment my brain could not distinguish between the lychee juice and actually eating lychee. it was a truly ethereal experience. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; unfortunately my brain is now attuned to the difference. I would like to experience that again one day &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/details&gt; &lt;details class="tofu"&gt; &lt;summary&gt;shout out to tofu&lt;span&gt; 7/19/2024&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/summary&gt; &lt;p&gt; I just had some AWESOME tofu and just felt the need to shout tofu out &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;tofu has a beautiful texture. I love tofu so much&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/details&gt; &lt;details class="mooncakes"&gt; &lt;summary&gt;shout out to mooncakes&lt;span&gt; 7/19/2024&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/summary&gt; &lt;p&gt; it's not currently tết (lunar new year) or anything but my thoughts wait for no holiday &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; one time I ate a mooncake as a kid and I foolishly thought the mooncake would be sweet, because I had known cakes to be sweet. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; unfortunately the mooncake I had that day had EGG in it, and it was not sweet! an unpleasant surprise for my younger self! &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I like mooncakes in present day.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/details&gt; &lt;details class="vegan-chicken"&gt; &lt;summary&gt;shout out to vegan chicken&lt;span&gt; 7/24/2024&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/summary&gt; &lt;p&gt; so I’m not vegan but I eat vegan chicken on occasion and. my goodness. vegan chicken tastes amazing. there’s just something about it! the texture, the slight tinge of vegetable sweetness mixed in, it’s really divine. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; I like chicken normally but I personally like vegan chicken better it’s such a unique taste &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/details&gt; &lt;details class="blue-cheese"&gt; &lt;summary&gt;shout out to blue cheese&lt;span&gt; 9/5/2024&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/summary&gt; &lt;p&gt; when I was a lot younger&lt;br/&gt; one day&lt;br/&gt; my mom brought home a big and strange looking cheese&lt;br/&gt; she was cutting off and eating slices of it&lt;br/&gt; I wanted to try&lt;br/&gt; I thought it would taste similar to other cheese &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; …&lt;br/&gt; it did not&lt;br/&gt; I remember it&lt;br/&gt; the flavor was so intense&lt;br/&gt; intensely abhorrent&lt;br/&gt; it did not feel like food. I do not know how to accurately describe the experience. it was an entirely unique kind of “sensation” of “pain” that I had never known before.&lt;br/&gt; I thought I was going to die!&lt;br/&gt; it lingered in my head for so so long and it was torment the entire time&lt;br/&gt; I could not feel or think about anything else&lt;br/&gt; to this day&lt;br/&gt; it is the worst thing I have ever eaten. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; I would only recommend eating a slice of blue cheese if you want to feel grateful for every other food you will ever eat in your entire life &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; if you are reading this and you enjoy blue cheese&lt;br/&gt; then I am glad that you are able to live a life where you can find joy even in such a strange food. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/details&gt; &lt;details class="pho"&gt; &lt;summary&gt;shout out to pho&lt;span&gt; 9/8/2024&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/summary&gt; &lt;p&gt; ok. pho. that is classics of vietnamese meal. honestly I think it’s kinda overrated compared to other vietnamese foods but I digress. today I want to tell you a story! &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; sometimes mom made pho for us for dinner! but I am a picky child! and I do not like the green bits in pho. so I ask my mom next time please make it without green bits! &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; my mom said it would not taste good without green bits but she wanted to teach me a lesson, so she agreed. and next time she made it without green bits. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I was so excited for pho without green bits!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; …&lt;br/&gt; pho without green bits…&lt;br/&gt; the smell is so pungent…it is too intense…it’s not good!&lt;br/&gt; I could barely eat it because the smell kept getting in the way!&lt;br/&gt; I never asked for pho without green bits again! &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; this is my warning! I recommend always cook pho with the green bits! &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; (I like green bits now as an adult because I am no longer as picky) &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;ADDENDUM&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; I do appreciate pho for it's qualities of being extremely filling. It is the most filling food I've ever had. A single bowl of pho and I am full for the entire day. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; It's great that a lot of people really like it! I have memories of going out with friends on a special event, and they pretty much always want pho. And because the bowls are so big, it's typically shared between us. It's nice to share food. Food brings us together. In that end, I am glad that lots of people enjoy pho, and it is nice to share a meal with other people. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Eating food for a special occasion feels special in itself.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/details&gt; &lt;p&gt; Of course, I will continue to consume until the end of my days; I look forward to the food of the future! &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Eat well,&lt;br/&gt;Espy&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="addendum"&gt; &lt;p&gt; By the way, my favorite food is "bánh ướt". The defining feature that I like about this food is "chả lụa", which is basically like pork sausage. But it's very different than most western sausages! It has a spongy texture and is usually eaten cold. It is the best meat ever. It's been so long since I had it. Guess I need to make a trip to the international supermarket myself. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The other defining feature that I like is the fried red onion. I could eat spoonfuls of that stuff. Even as a kid who hated onions, fried red onions were an exception. And the other &lt;i&gt;other&lt;/i&gt; defining feature that I like is the rice noodle sheets. I imagine this meal was probably invented by someone who had a bunch of rice noodle sheets laying around but didn't really want to make noodles out of them. As for the taste, I don't know to describe it. It's just the best thing I've ever had. Texture and taste. And fish sauce! It goes so well with so many things. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; This isn't really a dish that you eat in restaurants or anything. It's sort of a..."let's just make whatever with whatever we have" sort of dish, hence the usage of rice noodle sheets but not actually turning them into rice noodles. It's so simple and yet...despite everything, it is a meal with many memories to me. Memories of being fed and eating something delicious. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;img src="/img/embed/banh-uot.jpg"/&gt; &lt;p&gt;[CAPTION] A typical serving of bánh ướt according to Wikipedia as of writing. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://espy.world/log/2024/sep/shout%20out%20to%20food.html" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2024-09-16T05:42:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2024-09-16T05:42:00-07:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>espimyte</name>
    </author>
    <category term="thoughts"/>
	<category term="food"/>
</entry>

<entry>
    <id>https://espy.world/log/2024/sep/cohost%20posts%20archive.html</id>
    <title>cohost posts archive</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt; Following cohost's final days, I've decided to archive some of my non-art/non-project cohost posts here. Including the drafts that I never posted. Enjoy. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;(The food ones get a special post! Stay tuned.)&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="cohost" style="border-style: solid; border-width: 1px; padding: 5px"&gt; &lt;p&gt; a computer can do in an instant what would take me hours to do on my own. whenever I watch a computer take a long time to do something, I think about how long it would take me to do it. if the computer's taking a long time, how long would it have taken me? the sheer scale of it... &lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="divider"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="bottom"&gt; &lt;div class="cohost-tags"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;span class="post-date"&gt;UNPOSTED&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="cohost" style="border-style: solid; border-width: 1px; padding: 5px"&gt; &lt;p&gt; I love having little trinkets around…I have this tiny blue elephant and I love it. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="divider"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="bottom"&gt; &lt;div class="cohost-tags"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;span class="post-date"&gt;UNPOSTED&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="cohost" style="border-style: solid; border-width: 1px; padding: 5px"&gt; &lt;p&gt; there's too many websites. there's not enough websites. there needs to be less websites. there needs to be more websites. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="divider"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="bottom"&gt; &lt;div class="cohost-tags"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;span class="post-date"&gt;UNPOSTED&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="cohost" style="border-style: solid; border-width: 1px; padding: 5px"&gt; &lt;p&gt; at the end of a northernlion video he comes out of the screen and kills you. it’s been known to happen. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="divider"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="bottom"&gt; &lt;div class="cohost-tags"&gt; &lt;span class="cohost-tag"&gt;#northernlion&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cohost-tag"&gt;#lying&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;span class="post-date"&gt;UNPOSTED&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="cohost" style="border-style: solid; border-width: 1px; padding: 5px"&gt; &lt;p&gt; I have been trying to cook more, and I feel myself getting experience. I feel like I have an exp bar and soon I will level up my cooking skill &lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="divider"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="bottom"&gt; &lt;div class="cohost-tags"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;span class="post-date"&gt;UNPOSTED&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="cohost" style="border-style: solid; border-width: 1px; padding: 5px"&gt; &lt;p&gt; I like vehicles….conceptually. actually I do not know much about them and I am not a true vehicle enjoyer. Ahh! &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; I met a couple of people in my life that were really into cars. I remember this moment clearly. At a stoplight, one of them pointed to a car and asked me if I knew what it was. I didn’t. And then he told me all about that car and how it was a super rare car from overseas and it was really cool to see right in front of us on the road. He was so excited! And I could not comprehend the rarity of the car I was looking at, and I would have passed by this car unaware if not for the car enthusiast telling me about it. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; It was like someone seeing a shiny pokemon and trying to explain why it was so cool to someone that did not know pokemon. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Moments like that remind me that the world is very big with lots of different kinds of interests. Cars are not a unknown topic by any means, but listening to someone talk about this one extremely specific car really drove home to me how much there is in the world, and how little I know of it in comparision. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="divider"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="bottom"&gt; &lt;div class="cohost-tags"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;span class="post-date"&gt;UNPOSTED&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="cohost" style="border-style: solid; border-width: 1px; padding: 5px"&gt; &lt;p&gt; reminiscing on certain memories. I cannot accurately describe the fear when encountering a creature you have never seen or heard of before in your entire life when you are not expecting any creatures at all! when the fear has passed, it is an exciting memory &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; I remember looking under a microscope. a new world! lots of still things. and then suddenly! an alien looking creature whizzes by my vision! it was so cute and also so scary! it looked so unique. its visage is burned into my memory. maybe I will draw it someday. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="divider"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="bottom"&gt; &lt;div class="cohost-tags"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;span class="post-date"&gt;9/5/2024&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt; NOTE - Here's photos of the creature in question! If it even is a creature. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="img-row"&gt; &lt;img src="/img/embed/creature-1.jpg" style="width: 50%"/&gt; &lt;img src="/img/embed/creature-2.jpg" style="width: 50%"/&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="cohost" style="border-style: solid; border-width: 1px; padding: 5px"&gt; &lt;p&gt; done with coding for today and I keep opening up godot and github instinctively. I have to get out of here &lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="divider"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="bottom"&gt; &lt;div class="cohost-tags"&gt; &lt;span class="cohost-tag"&gt;#coding&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cohost-tag"&gt;#gamedev&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;span class="post-date"&gt;9/2/2024&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="cohost" style="border-style: solid; border-width: 1px; padding: 5px"&gt; &lt;p&gt; today I am thinking about the various ways "fishing" is designed in games. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="divider"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="bottom"&gt; &lt;p class="cohost-tags"&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;span class="post-date"&gt;8/30/2024&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt; NOTE - To the one who was interested in reading more about this, if you are reading this now: I still intend to write my thoughts out! &lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="cohost" style="border-style: solid; border-width: 1px; padding: 5px"&gt; &lt;img src="/img/embed/infinite-wealth-possible.png" style="margin-top: 20px"/&gt; &lt;p&gt;just started playing yakuza infinite wealth&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="divider"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="bottom"&gt; &lt;div class="cohost-tags"&gt; &lt;span class="cohost-tag"&gt;#yakuza&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cohost-tag"&gt;#yakuza infinite wealth&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cohost-tag"&gt;#yakuza 8&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;span class="post-date"&gt;8/18/2024&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="cohost" style="border-style: solid; border-width: 1px; padding: 5px"&gt; &lt;p&gt;never should’ve smoked that shit now I’m in wet dry world&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="divider"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="bottom"&gt; &lt;div class="cohost-tags"&gt; &lt;span class="cohost-tag"&gt;#northernlion&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cohost-tag"&gt;#super mario 64&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;span class="post-date"&gt;8/12/2024&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="cohost" style="border-style: solid; border-width: 1px; padding: 5px"&gt; &lt;p&gt; I do not know the difference between “good” code and “bad” code. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="divider"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="bottom"&gt; &lt;p class="cohost-tags"&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;span class="post-date"&gt;7/4/2024&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="cohost" style="border-style: solid; border-width: 1px; padding: 5px"&gt; &lt;p&gt; so much! so many experiences I want to EXPERIENCE! so many experiences I want to CREATE! so many different kind of meals I want to EAT! so many games I want to PLAY! so much, so much! &lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="divider"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="bottom"&gt; &lt;p class="cohost-tags"&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;span class="post-date"&gt;6/10/2024&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="cohost" style="border-style: solid; border-width: 1px; padding: 5px"&gt; &lt;div style="display: flex; margin-top: 20px"&gt; &lt;img class="rotate-planet" src="/img/embed/circle-1.gif" style="width: 20%"/&gt; &lt;img class="rotate-planet" src="/img/embed/circle-2.gif" style="width: 20%"/&gt; &lt;img class="rotate-planet" src="/img/embed/circle-3.gif" style="width: 20%"/&gt; &lt;img class="rotate-planet" src="/img/embed/circle-4.gif" style="width: 20%"/&gt; &lt;img class="rotate-planet" src="/img/embed/circle-5.gif" style="width: 20%"/&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;img src="/img/embed/people-who-rotate.png" style="margin-top: 20px"/&gt; &lt;div class="divider"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="bottom"&gt; &lt;div class="cohost-tags"&gt; &lt;span class="cohost-tag"&gt;#3d&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cohost-tag"&gt;#chulip&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cohost-tag"&gt;#they are people to me&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;span class="post-date"&gt;6/1/2024&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="cohost" style="border-style: solid; border-width: 1px; padding: 5px"&gt; &lt;p&gt;OHHHHHH MY GOD!!!!!! (spins at 3600 rpm)&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="divider"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="bottom"&gt; &lt;p class="cohost-tags"&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;span class="post-date"&gt;5/18/2024&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="cohost" style="border-style: solid; border-width: 1px; padding: 5px"&gt; &lt;p&gt; I feel like rohan using heaven’s door whenever I use “inspect element” &lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="divider"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="bottom"&gt; &lt;div class="cohost-tags"&gt; &lt;span class="cohost-tag"&gt;#JoJo's Bizarre Adventure&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cohost-tag"&gt;#diamond is unbreakable&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cohost-tag"&gt;#rohan kishibe&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;span class="post-date"&gt;5/10/2024&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="cohost" style="border-style: solid; border-width: 1px; padding: 5px"&gt; &lt;p&gt; learning to play mahjong was one of the best decisions I’ve ever made. It truly was worth every effort. one day I’d like to write about what I enjoy so much about this game and what it means to me &lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="divider"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="bottom"&gt; &lt;div class="cohost-tags"&gt; &lt;span class="cohost-tag"&gt;#mahjong&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;span class="post-date"&gt;4/6/2024&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;NOTE - I still want to write about it.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="cohost" style="border-style: solid; border-width: 1px; padding: 5px"&gt; &lt;div style="display: flex; margin-top: 20px"&gt; &lt;img src="/img/embed/espeon-rimworld-1.png" style="width: 50%"/&gt;&lt;img src="/img/embed/espeon-rimworld-2.png" style="width: 50%"/&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;had a surplus of cloth so I made an espeon out of carpet&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="divider"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="bottom"&gt; &lt;div class="cohost-tags"&gt; &lt;span class="cohost-tag"&gt;#rimworld&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cohost-tag"&gt;#pokemon&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cohost-tag"&gt;#espeon&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;span class="post-date"&gt;3/20/2024&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="cohost" style="border-style: solid; border-width: 1px; padding: 5px"&gt; &lt;p&gt;going to the north. hope I get to see the lion&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="divider"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="bottom"&gt; &lt;div class="cohost-tags"&gt; &lt;span class="cohost-tag"&gt;#northernlion&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;span class="post-date"&gt;3/9/2024&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="cohost" style="border-style: solid; border-width: 1px; padding: 5px"&gt; &lt;p&gt; been playing splatoon 3 side order and im having a good time, it’s been inspiring me and lifting my mood. beat it the day after its release I almost forgot how much I love splatoon also it’s a roguelike and I love roguelikes &lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="divider"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="bottom"&gt; &lt;div class="cohost-tags"&gt; &lt;span class="cohost-tag"&gt;#splatoon&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cohost-tag"&gt;#splatoon 3&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cohost-tag"&gt;#side order&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;span class="post-date"&gt;2/25/2024&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="cohost" style="border-style: solid; border-width: 1px; padding: 5px"&gt; &lt;p&gt; fun tip if you have side order: while outside of the spire, run around in a circle for a bit for a surprise &lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="divider"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="bottom"&gt; &lt;div class="cohost-tags"&gt; &lt;span class="cohost-tag"&gt;#splatoon&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cohost-tag"&gt;#splatoon 3&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="cohost-tag"&gt;#side order&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;span class="post-date"&gt;2/25/2024&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="cohost" style="border-style: solid; border-width: 1px; padding: 5px"&gt; &lt;p&gt;I like the sound of mahjong tiles&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; It is so cool how the tiles drop when you reveal your hand in mahjong. it is so cool to go “RON” and reveal ur epic yakuman. man. man. this is the best game ever &lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="divider"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="bottom"&gt; &lt;div class="cohost-tags"&gt; &lt;span class="cohost-tag"&gt;#mahjong&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;span class="post-date"&gt;11/24/2023&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="cohost" style="border-style: solid; border-width: 1px; padding: 5px"&gt; &lt;p&gt; I want to take a moment to express my gratitude to those that have left comments on my posts, even if I haven't replied. I appreciate that you've taken the time to express how you feel about something I've made, and I'm thankful. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="divider"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="bottom"&gt; &lt;p class="cohost-tags"&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;span class="post-date"&gt;4/12/2024&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;img class="pinned" src="/svg/pin.svg" style="display: none"/&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="cohost" style="border-style: solid; border-width: 1px; padding: 5px"&gt; &lt;p&gt; the idea that everyone could live together peacefully was always a "stupid pipe dream" of mine. but maybe miracles are possible? &lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="divider"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="bottom"&gt; &lt;p class="cohost-tags"&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;span class="post-date"&gt;UNPOSTED&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;img class="pinned" src="/svg/pin.svg" style="display: none"/&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div&gt; &lt;p&gt;Sayanora,&lt;br/&gt;Espy&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="cohost-button"&gt; &lt;a href="https://mykocalico.neocities.org/buttons"&gt;&lt;img src="/img/embed/cohost-button.gif"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://espy.world/log/2024/sep/cohost%20posts%20archive.html" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2024-09-15T01:31:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2024-09-15T01:31:00-07:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>espimyte</name>
    </author>
    <category term="thoughts"/>
	<category term="misc"/>
</entry>

<entry>
    <id>https://espy.world/log/2024/sep/RSS%20support%20now%20available..html</id>
    <title>RSS support now available.</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt; I finally got time to work on this. Had my hands full for a while and did not expect the Cohost shutdown so soon. The shutdown of Cohost has called me into action to support RSS on the site. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; If you wish to be free from the instability of the social media, an RSS feed is now available for you to use so you may keep up with my various musings in art and code and maybe some other things also. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The RSS feed is linked below! It will also be found on the index of the site. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="rss"&gt; &lt;a class="rss-link" href="/feed.xml"&gt; &lt;div class="rss" style="margin: 0"&gt; &lt;img class="rss-image" src="/svg/rss-green.svg" style="margin: 0; height: 1em; width: 20px"/&gt;&lt;span&gt; ["Hi, I'm the RSS feed!"]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt; Currently, the feed supports several category of posts. They are explained below. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;td&gt;SITE&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td&gt;Significant site related updates, like this one.&lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;td&gt;GALLERY&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td&gt;New art.&lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;td&gt;COMIC&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td&gt;New comics.&lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;td&gt;PROJECT&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td&gt;Project related posts.&lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;td&gt;THOUGHTS&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td&gt;My random thoughts that I wrote down and feel like sharing.&lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;td&gt;ESPEON&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td&gt; I've been keeping a collection of Espeon effigies. I intend to take over the world with them. This is for updates for my growing plan of world domination. &lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;td&gt;MISC&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td&gt;Anything that doesn't fit with the other categories.&lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;/table&gt; &lt;p&gt; If you wish to know how to use RSS feeds, or set one up for your own sites, there are plenty of resources online that can help. There are a lot of programs and apps that can help you read RSS feeds, and there are tutorials to help with creating an RSS feed of your own (which only requires you to add a &lt;code&gt;feed.xml&lt;/code&gt; file to your site). &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; I haven't really been sharing much stuff online lately. I promise the desire to create is still alive within me. Just perhaps in a coma at the moment. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Until then...&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="audio-div"&gt; &lt;audio controls=""&gt; &lt;source src="/audio/see-you-next-time.mp3" type="audio/mp3"/&gt; &lt;/audio&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;p class="quote" style="margin-bottom: 5px"&gt;"See you next time!"&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="quote" style="margin-top: 0"&gt;- Dolce Kamiya from Yakuza 0&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Best regards,&lt;br/&gt;Espy&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://espy.world/log/2024/sep/RSS%20support%20now%20available..html" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2024-09-13T03:54:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2024-09-13T03:54:00-07:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>espimyte</name>
    </author>
    <category term="site"/>
</entry>

<entry>
    <id>https://espy.world/log/2024/jun/Release%20of%20EYECRYPT%21.html</id>
    <title>Release of EYECRYPT!</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt; I spent a week or so toiling on something I’ve wanted to create for years now, and I’ve finally finished! &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; EYECRYPT is a tool that visualizes the effect of primitive encryption methods on an image! &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; I couldn’t find anything online that could perform this process, so I decided to take matters into my own hands and make the tool myself to allow this process to be accessible to others. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; To use it is simple, simply plug in any image of your choice and let EYECRYPT work its magic! &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This has the end result of making images go from this:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;img src="/img/eyecrypt/blossom.png"/&gt; &lt;p&gt;To this:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;img src="/img/eyecrypt/blossom-result.png"/&gt; &lt;p&gt; These visual effects are only possible due to the vulnerabilities of encryption methods that allow patterns to be discerned. Though ill-advised for the use of actual obfuscation of data, I find the visual effect of these encryption methods to be rather compelling and beautiful, and I hope this tool can allow others to be able to experiment with this effect as well. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2&gt;You can download it here:&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/eyecrypt.html"&gt;/eyecrypt.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Happy encrypting,&lt;br/&gt;Espy&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="addendum"&gt; &lt;h2&gt;ADDENDUM&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt; Now that I have a proper blog, I'm going to share an unposted cohost draft where I wrote about the developement of this program. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="quote"&gt; "I recently released a tool online for the first time, and I gotta say, it felt so rewarding to figure out how to make an executable that didn't require any external installations. It made me feel so happy testing it out with my partner and seeing them actually be able to run and open the program just like that. I really wanted it to be as accessible as I could, I didn't want anyone to be blocked by having to install other stuff themselves." &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="quote"&gt; "The original version of the program required the user to install both ImageMagick and OpenSSL. ImageMagick is a simple enough installation, but OpenSSL? Not exactly the most user friendly to the average layman, even if I do provide additional instructions and help myself. Either way, requiring any external installation is enough to demotivate most people from my experience, especially for a program made by some rando like me." &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="quote"&gt; "Ideally I’d also like to develop a web version. That, however, would take some time since I need to do some research on how that would work cuz I’m not already familiar, but it’d be a dream come true if I could make it so anyone could try it without having to download anything." &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; If you ever make anything cool with EYECRYPT, I'd love to see it! &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://espy.world/log/2024/jun/Release%20of%20EYECRYPT%21.html" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2024-06-13T21:44:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2024-06-13T21:44:00-07:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>espimyte</name>
    </author>
    <category term="project"/>
	<category term="code"/>
</entry>

<entry>
    <id>https://espy.world/log/2024/apr/on%20explaining%20mahjong.html</id>
    <title>on explaining mahjong</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;img src="/img/embed/mahjong-is-a-game-of-skill.jpeg" style="margin-top: 10px"/&gt; &lt;p&gt;[CAPTION] "mahjong is a game of skill"&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The above is a screenshot of a recent hand I won in the game "Mahjong Soul". &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; I’ve been thinking about how I would explain this to someone who doesn’t know mahjong about why the scenario depicted in this image is notable, and it was a reminder to me of how complex mahjong can be. I’ve gotten so used to all the terminology and flow of the game that I forgot how intimidating it was to first learn this game. in a way, remembering how I could barely even comprehend the game at first to how I know the game now makes me love mahjong even more. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; it reminds me of learning a deck in yugioh. it can be extremely complex to get the hang of, but once you do, it feels almost like the deck is a part of your body. it’s fused with you, the heart of the cards and your heart are one and the same! you’re connected! &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; feeling the incomprehensible become comprehensible. making it across the gap in your mind from where you couldn’t understand, to having such an understanding that it’s difficult to imagine not having it. that shift is what I love. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; it’s something I love about learning systems in general, not even just in games. really immersing yourself in it and feeling it become second nature to you, almost like another sense. it’s just incredible. and games hold so many systems to learn. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; P.S. You may have noticed that in this entire entry I did not, in fact, actually explain this image. I would like to, but I am feeling far too lazy at the moment. Perhaps another time! &lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="addendum"&gt; &lt;h2&gt;ADDENDUM&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;"Perhaps another time", I said. And that time is now.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; I will not be explaining how to play mahjong, but I'm going to try my best to attempt to at least explain as simply as possible why this image is notable. For experienced mahjong players, this image tells a story. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; In a typical game of mahjong, there are 4 players. Players will participate in several rounds to try and accumulate the most points. In each round, players start out with a certain number of tiles. They will draw new tiles and discard tiles. To win a round, you must complete a valid hand before anyone else. When you complete a valid hand, you will win the round and get points. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The screenshot is an example of a winning hand.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; I'm not going to go over what makes a hand valid or not. You don't need to know that for this specifically. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; "Riichi" is something you can call when you are one away from a winning hand. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Hands are scored using "Yaku". And there are a LOT of yaku in the game. The only yaku you need to understand for now is "Double Riichi" and "Ippatsu". Don't worry about the other ones. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;b&gt;Double Riichi&lt;/b&gt; - A special kind of riichi you call when the tiles you draw when the round starts are already one away from a winning hand. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;b&gt;Ippatsu&lt;/b&gt; - A yaku that is achieved by completing a hand with the very next tile you draw after you declare riichi. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; So what do these two yaku existing in the same winning hand tell us? &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; It tells us that this round started with someone being one away from a winning hand, and then immedietly drawing the tile they needed right after. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; In other words, this screenshot tells the story of an extremely short round where one person just wins based on insane luck and no other players stood a chance. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; A round that has the winning player (me) smiling like an idiot and the other players hitting me with a cold stare. Heheh. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;And now you know!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;img src="/img/embed/riichi-stare.png" style="width: 400px"/&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://espy.world/log/2024/apr/on%20explaining%20mahjong.html" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2024-04-25T00:00:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2024-04-25T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>espimyte</name>
    </author>
    <category term="thoughts"/>
</entry>

</feed>
